So this works for things other than words. The place where
递归定义同样适用于造词之外的其他问题
you've seen it the most so far has been in language,
递归定义可以应用于目前你在这门语言中所遇见的大部分场景
but we're also going to to see how to use it to
但是接下来我们也要探讨怎么将这一概念用于
make procedures. And you'll also see how to use it in
制作过程 而且你也将看到怎么把递归定义应用在
later classes, how to define data structures. There are lots and
后面会介绍到的类 以及如何定义数据结构 有很多
lots of different things in computing that are defined recursively. And
很多关于计算的问题都是出现递归定义的内容
a recursive definition has two parts. It has the base case.
递归定义由两部分组成 它有一个基本情况
In our example with the word, that was the second rule.
在我们关于 word 的例子中 说的就是第二条造词规则
And the base case we can think of as
对于这个基本情况我们可以把它看做一种
a starting point. And the important thing about the base
定义的起点 而基本情况的重要性在于
case, is it's not defined in terms of itself. It
它不是按照 word 来定义 word 自身 它
has to be something where we already know how to
是我们已经明确了如何定义 word 的一种情况
define it. So for programs, it's usually going to be the
所以对于程序来说 基本情况的这一定义将会是
smallest input, or one of the simplest inputs. Something where
输入量最少的 或者说是输入最简单的一种情况 也就是说
we already know the answer. We don't have to do
我们通过基本情况的定义就可以得到 word 的具体内容 我们不需要
any computation to figure it out. The second part is
做任何进一步的计算就可以得到 word 的内容 第二部分是
the recursive case. And that is defined in terms of itself.
递归情况 这种情况是按照 word 来对 word 自身做的定义
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[书写中]
But it shouldn't be defined in terms of
但是 word 并不能完全按照 word 自身来做定义
itself exactly. It should be defined in terms of
它应该是按照
some sort of smaller version of itself. We need
某些基于 word 做出定义后的子版本做定义 我们需要
to make progress to eventually get to the base
继续进行定义的过程 直到最后关于基本情况的定义
case. We'll see what that means in programs
很快我们就会知道对于程序而言这意味着什么
soon. First, we're going to try one other example not
首先 我们将尝试通过其他一些例子来说明
in terms of a program, just to get a
而不是按照程序来进行说明 这只是
better sense for how things can be defined recursively.
为了我们能够更好地理解如何通过递归的过程来实现更好的定义